<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CookingBOYS</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="sign">Sign</string>
    <string name="forgot">Forgot</string>
    <string name="user">Username</string>
    <string name="pass">Password</string>
    <string name="ok">OKd</string>
    <string name="meats">Meats</string>
    <string name="seafoods">Seafoods</string>
    <string name="vegetable">Vegetable</string>
    <string name="search">Search</string>
    <string name="x">X</string>
    <string name="adobo">adobo</string>
    <string name="beefsteak">beefsteak</string>
    <string name="sini">sini</string>
    <string name="paksiw">Paksiw</string>
    <string name="hipon">Hipon</string>
    <string name="tahong">tahong</string>
    <string name="chopseuy">chopseuy</string>
    <string name="pakbet">pakbet</string>
    <string name="mongo">mongo</string>
    <string name="about_us">AboutUs</string>

    <string name="about_us_names">Created By: \n
    Verzosa, John Paul M. \n
    Yumul, John Kenneth C. \n
    Molito, Aldwin B. \n\n
    2023</string>

    <string name="about_us1">We are a group of 3rd Year Students from NEW ERA UNIVERSITY came up with the idea of creating an app related on food section, we call it the "The Cooking Boys" app.</string>
    <string name="about_us2">Our team are called as "Cooking Juan'D", the "Juan" represents the Filipino people and the "Cooking" symbolizes the love of the Filipino people in cooking. </string>
    <string name="about_us3">Our chosen app can be use as a guide for someone who wants to try a Filipino dish, our app includes the ingredients and cooking instruction for a specific dish.</string>
    <string name="about_us4">The chosen dishes for our app are the most popular and well known dishes in the Philippines and almost the entire Filipino people knows about it.</string>
    <string name="about_us5">We thank you for using this app and viewing some of the most delicious dishes here in the Philippines.</string>
    <string name="about_us7">Happy studying! \n\n -The Cooking Juan’D </string>

    <string name="adoborecipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 2 tbsp canola oil \n
        ● 6 cloves garlic crushed \n
        ● 1 pc onion, sliced \n
        ● 1 kilogram chicken cut ups \n
        ● 2 tbsp vinegar \n
        ● 1/4 cup soy sauce \n
        ● 1 cup water \n
        ● 2 pcs bay leaves \n
        ● 1 tsp whole black peppercorns, slightly crushed \n
        ● 2 pc Knorr chicken cubes \n
        ● 1 tsp brown sugar packed \n
        ● Option: 1 cup kale or spinach</string>

    <string name="adoboinstructions">Instructions: \n
        1 Heat oil in pan and sauté garlic and onions. Then add chicken to the pan and \n
        sear on all sides, until you have a little browning in the chicken skin. \n
        2 Pour in vinegar, soy sauce and water. Add bay leaves, pepper and Knorr \n
        Chicken Cubes. Bring to a boil over high heat then reduce heat to simmer, but do \n
        not cover the pan. Continue to simmer for 10 mins. \n
        3 Remove chicken pieces from sauce and fry in another pan until nicely \n
        browned. \n
        4 Put back fried chicken pieces into sauce. Add sugar and let simmer again for \n
        another 10 minutes or until sauce has thickened. Serve warm. </string>

    <string name="sinigangrecipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 2 pounds pork spare ribs, cut into 2-inch pieces \n
        ● 8 cups water \n
        ● 2 large tomatoes, quartered \n
        ● 1 medium onion, peeled and quartered \n
        ● 2 tablespoons fish sauce \n
        ● 6 pieces gabi \n
        ● 1 6-inch radish (labanos) \n
        ● 2 finger chilies (siling haba) \n
        ● 1/2 bunch long beans (sitaw) \n
        ● 1 eggplant \n
        ● 6 pieces okra, ends trimmed \n
        ● 15 pieces large tamarind \n
        ● salt and pepper to taste \n
        ● 1 bunch bok choy or pechay</string>

    <string name="sinigang1">Instructions: \n
        1. Rinse pork ribs and drain well. \n
        2. In a pot over medium heat, combine pork and enough water to cover. Bring to a \n
        boil, skimming scum that accumulates on top. \n
        3. Once broth clears, add tomatoes, onion, and fish sauce. Lower heat and simmer \n
        for about 1 to 1 1/2 hours or until meat is tender, adding more water as \n
        necessary to maintain about 8 cups. \n
        4. Add gabi and cook for about 4 to 6 minutes or until tender. \n
        5. Add chili peppers and radish. Continue to simmer for about 2 to 3 minutes. \n
        6. Add long beans. Continue to cook for about 2 minutes. \n
        7. Add eggplant and okra and cook for another 1 to 2 minutes. \n
        8. If using packaged tamarind base, add to the pot and stir until completely \n
        dissolved. \n
        9. Season with salt and pepper to taste. \n
        10.Add bok choy and continue to cook for about 1 minute. Serve hot.</string>

    <string name="beef_recipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 2 pounds top round or sirloin, sliced thinly \n
        ● 2 lemons, juiced (about 1/4 cup juice) \n
        ● 1/4 cup soy sauce \n
        ● 1 onion, peeled and sliced thinly \n
        ● 1 head garlic, peeled and minced \n
        ● 1/4 teaspoon pepper \n
        ● 3 tablespoons canola oil \n
        ● 1 cup water \n
        ● salt to taste \n
        ● 1 onion, peeled and sliced into rings</string>

    <string name="beef_instructions">Instructions: \n
        1. In a bowl, combine beef, lemon juice, soy sauce, sliced onions, garlic, and \n
        pepper. Massage marinade into the meat and marinate for about 30 minutes. \n
        2. Remove meat, onions, and garlic from marinade, squeezing and reserving excess liquid. \n
        3. In a pan over high heat, heat oil. Add beef and cook for about 3 to 5 minutes per \n
        side or until lightly browned. Spoon out and reserve released meat juices during frying. Remove meat. \n
        4. In the pan, add onions and garlic, and cook, stirring regularly, until softened. Return browned beef to pan. \n
        5. Add reserved marinade and meat juices. Add water and bring to a boil. \n
        6. Cover, lower heat, and simmer for about 40 to 50 minutes or until meat is \n
        fork-tender and liquid is reduced. Season with salt to taste. \n
        7. Turn off heat. Garnish with onion rings, if desired, and cover to allow onions to \n
        cook slightly in the steam. Serve hot</string>

    <string name="shrimp_recipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 2 lbs shrimp cleaned \n
        ● 2 tablespoons parsley chopped \n
        ● 1/4 cup butter \n
        ● 1 head garlic crushed \n
        ● 1 cup lemon lime soda \n
        ● 1 teaspoon lemon juice \n
        ● salt and pepper to taste</string>

    <string name="shrimp_instruction">Instructions: \n
        1. Marinate the shrimp in lemon soda for about 10 minutes \n
        2. Melt the butter in a pan. \n
        3. Add the garlic. Cook in low heat until the color turns light brown \n
        4. Put-in the shrimp. Adjust heat to high. Stir-fry until shrimp turns orange. \n
        5. Season with ground black pepper, salt, and lemon juice. Stir. \n
        6. Add parsley. Cook for 30 seconds. \n
        7. Serve hot. Share and Enjoy! \n </string>

    <string name="paksiw_recipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 1 1/2 lbs. milkfish cleaned and sliced crosswise into serving pieces \n
        ● 3 thumbs ginger crushed \n
        ● 5 cloves garlic crushed \n
        ● 1/2 cup white vinegar \n
        ● 1 cup water \n
        ● 1 piece onion sliced \n
        ● 1 piece Chinese eggplant chopped \n
        ● 5 pieces okra \n
        ● 2 pieces long green pepper \n
        ● 1 teaspoon whole peppercorn \n
        ● Salt to taste</string>

    <string name="paksiw_instruction">Instructions: \n
        1. Arrange ginger, garlic, okra, onion, long green pepper, \n
        peppercorn, and eggplant on the pot. \n
        2. Top with bangus slices. \n
        3. Pour water and vinegar. Apply heat and let boil. Cover and \n
        continue to cook in low to medium heat for 15 minutes. \n
        4. Add salt to taste. \n
        5. Transfer to a serving plate. Serve. \n
        6. Share and enjoy! </string>

    <string name="baked_recipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 2 lbs mussels tahong, cleaned and boiled until the shells open \n
        ● 1/2 cup butter softened \n
        ● 7 cloves garlic pounded and minced \n
        ● 1 cup quickmelt cheese grated </string>

    <string name="baked_instructions">Instructions: \n
        1. Preheat oven to 375 degrees Fahrenheit. \n
        2. Combine butter and garlic then mix well. \n
        3. Remove the extra shell from the mussel. Place some butter and garlic mixture on \n
        the mussels using a teaspoon or brush. \n
        4. Top the mussels with grated quickmelt cheese. \n
        5. Arrange the mussels in a baking tray lined with Aluminum foil. \n
        6. Bake for 15 to 18 minutes. \n
        7. Remove from the oven and transfer to a serving plate. \n
        8. Serve as an appetizer dish. Share and enjoy! </string>

    <string name="chopseuy_recipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 7 pieces shrimp cleaned and deveined \n
        ● 3 ounces pork sliced \n
        ● 3 ounces boneless chicken breast sliced \n
        ● 1 ½ cup cauliflower florets \n
        ● 1 piece carrot sliced crosswise into thin pieces \n
        ● 15 pieces snow peas \n
        ● 8 pieces baby corn \n
        ● 1 piece red bell pepper sliced into squares \n
        ● 1 piece green bell pepper sliced into squares \n
        ● 1 ½ cups cabbage chopped \n
        ● 12 pieces quail eggs boiled \n
        ● 1 piece yellow onion sliced \n
        ● 4 cloves garlic crushed \n
        ● ¼ cup soy sauce \n
        ● 1 ½ tablespoons oyster sauce \n
        ● ¾ cup water \n
        ● 1 tablespoon cornstarch diluted in ½ cup water \n
        ● ¼ teaspoon ground black pepper \n
        ● 3 tablespoons cooking oil </string>

    <string name="chopseuy_instructions">Instructions: \n
        1. Heat oil in a wok or pan. \n
        2. Pan fry the shrimp for 1 minute per side. Remove from the wok. Set aside. \n
        3. Saute onion. Add garlic and continue to saute until the onion becomes soft. \n
        4. Add pork and chicken. Stir fry until light brown. \n
        5. Add soy sauce and oyster sauce. Stir. \n
        6. Pour water. Let boil. Cover and cook in medium heat for 15 minutes. \n
        7. Add cauliflower, carrots, bell peppers, snow peas, and young corn. Stir. \n
        8. Add cabbage. Toss. Cover and cook for 5 to 7 minutes. \n
        9. Put the pan-fried shrimp into the pot and add ground black pepper. \n
        10.Add the boiled quail eggs and cornstarch diluted in water. Toss. \n
        11.Transfer to a serving plate. Serve. \n
        12.Share and enjoy! </string>

    <string name="bean_recipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 1 cup dried mung beans \n
        ● 6 cups water \n
        ● 1 tablespoon vegetable oil \n
        ● 1 onion, peeled and sliced thinly \n
        ● 3 cloves garlic, peeled and minced \n
        ● 1 large tomato, chopped \n
        ● 2 cups chicharon (pork cracklings with attached meat) \n
        ● 1 bunch fresh spinach, stems trimmed \n
        ● 1 tablespoon fish sauce</string>

    <string name="bean_instructions">Instructions: \n
        1. Sort through the mung beans, discarding discolored or shriveled beans and \n
        any grit or dirt. Rinse beans in cold, running water until water runs clear. Drain well. \n
        2. In a large pot, combine mung beans and water. Over medium heat, bring to \n
        a boil skimming froth that floats on top. \n
        3. Lower heat, cover, and continue to cook for about 45 to 50 minutes or until \n
        beans have softened and skins have burst. Add more water as needed to \n
        maintain about 4 cups. \n
        4. In another pot over medium heat, heat oil. Add onions and garlic and cook \n
        until tender and aromatic. \n
        5. Add tomatoes and cook, mashing with the back of the spoon, until softened. \n
        6. Add fish sauce and continue to cook for about 1 to 2 minutes. \n
        7. Add cooked mung beans including liquid. Bring to a boil. \n
        8. Add pork cracklings and continue to cook until softened. Season with salt \n
        and pepper to taste. \n
        9. Add spinach, turn off heat and cover pot for about 1 to 2 minutes or until \n
        spinach is just wilted. Serve hot. </string>

    <string name="pakbet_recipe">Ingredients: \n
        ● 1 1/2 lbs. squash cubed \n
        ● 18 pieces string beans cut in 2-inch pieces \n
        ● 1 piece Knorr Pork cube \n
        ● 3 ounces pork sliced into small pieces, preferably boiled \n
        ● 4 cups coconut milk \n
        ● 1 piece onion chopped \n
        ● 2 thumbs ginger sliced into strips \n
        ● 5 cloves garlic crushed \n
        ● ¼ teaspoon ground black pepper \n
        ● 1 tablespoon cooking oil \n
        ● Fish sauce to taste </string>

    <string name="pakbet_instructions">Instructions: \n
        1. Heat oil in a pan. Add pork. Cook until brown and crispy. \n
        2. Sauté garlic, onion, and ginger. \n
        3. Once the onion softens, pour the coconut milk into the pan. Stir. Cover the pan \n
        and let the liquid boil. Once boiling, adjust the heat to medium and continue \n
        boiling for 5 minutes. \n
        4. Add Knorr Pork Cube and squash. Continue cooking for 5 minutes. \n
        5. Add string beans. Cook for 5 to 8 minutes. \n
        6. Season with ground black pepper and fish sauce as needed. \n
        7. Transfer to a serving plate. Serve with warm rice</string>




</resources>